THILINA RANASINGHE

Antioch, CA
Mobile: 925-247-4725
Email: thilina2002@gmail.com
LinkedIn | Website

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Vision-driven change agent with a career-long record of Web/Graphic Design, Web Development, and Desktop Support Administration success for leading organizations.

Proven talent for aligning business strategy and objectives with established **Desktop Support Administration and Web Development** paradigms to achieve maximum operational impacts with minimum resource expenditures. Growth-focused thought leader with over 15 years of experience creating engaging and eye-catching graphics and promotional materials. Exceptionally dedicated professional with keen interpersonal, communication, and organizational skills, as well as social media management, search engine optimization, and video editing expertise.

Core Competencies

- Web Design & Development.
- Graphic Design.
- PC/Mac Troubleshooting.
- Web Server Management. (cPanel / WHM) •
- Social Media Advertising & Management.
- IT Support & Consultation.

- Search Engine Optimization. (SEO)
- Video & Audio Editing.
- Network Administration.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

McCurley's Floor Centre, Inc., San Ramon, CA, Nov 2008 to Present

GRAPHICS WEB DESIGNER/SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER/SYSTEMS SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR

- Generate official websites of <u>www.MacFloor.com</u>, <u>www.ConcordFloor.com</u>, <u>www.MacFloors.com</u>, and design Web and Multimedia-based layouts as well as Graphics footage.
- Leverage Search Engine Optimization (SEO) strategies to drive engagement on official websites.
- Oversee web server administration, updates, and maintenance for official websites.
- Spearhead the development and implementation of official business pages across multiple social media channels including Facebook, YouTube, Instagram, Pinterest, LinkedIn, Houzz, NextDoor, and Twitter.
- Produce videos for YouTube and Vimeo channels using Adobe Premiere, Sony Vegas, and Garage Band.
- Compose text and design images for pay-per-click advertisements utilizing Google AdWords, Yahoo, and Bing AdWords, as well as Facebook and Instagram Ads.
- Create and update Blog pages as well as Local Business listing pages in all major local business listing websites including Google, Yahoo, Bing, Yelp, Better Business Bureau, MapQuest, and YellowPages.
- Direct digital and print advertising including banners, brochures, and email promotions.
- Contribute desktop support in addition to troubleshooting computer systems and maintaining wired and wireless local area networks and printers across multiple office locations in Northern California.

Previous Experience:

Independent Television Network Ltd., Sri Lanka, Nov 2005 to Sep 2008 | **COMPUTER 3D GRAPHICS ANIMATOR/WEB DEVELOPER.**

Art Media Promotion, Sri Lanka, Aug 2003 to Nov 2004 | GRAPHIC DESIGNER/IT SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR.

FREELANCE EXPERIENCE

Happy Day Montessori School, Albany, CA, Oct. 2020 to Present

GRAPHICS WEB DESIGNER/SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER/IT SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR

- Lead the design of the official website www.HappyDayMontessoriSchool.com and create Web and multimedia-based layouts and Graphics footage using Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Premiere.
- Apply SEO techniques to drive web traffic and contribute support for computers, printers, and networks.
- Devise videos for official YouTube channels using Adobe Premiere, Sony Vegas, and Garage Band.
- Establish Local Business Listing pages, create an official company logo and print marketing materials, and design graphics for e-mail promotions and e-mail greetings.

THILINA RANASINGHE Page 2

Time & Quality Construction Inc, Concord, CA, June 2020 to Present

GRAPHICS WEB DESIGNER/IT SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR

• Coordinate the design and management of the company's official website www.TnQConstruction.com using WordPress, and utilized SEO strategies to drive web traffic and engagement.

Regulate all web hosting and server management for the official website to reduce outages.

Anthony Santos, CPA, Dublin, CA, Nov 2019 to Present

GRAPHICS WEB DESIGNER/IT SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR

- Head web design of the group's website <u>www.AnthonySantosTax.com</u> using SEO techniques while handling web hosting and server management.
- Provide in-house and remote desktop support for the local computer system, scanners, printers, and network.

Forest Hills Preschool & Child Care Inc, Martinez, CA, Nov 2008 to Present

GRAPHICS WEB DESIGNER/SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER/IT SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR

- Launch the site <u>www.ForesHillsPreSchool.com</u>, create web and multimedia-based layouts and Graphics footage, generated copy using SEO strategies, and lead web hosting and server management.
- Introduce official business pages on Facebook as well as business listing pages.
- Construct brochures and handouts and contribute IT support across multiple systems.

EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS

Associate's in Art Digital Media and Web Development, Expected 2023

Diablo Valley College, Pleasant Hill, CA

Coursework towards a Bachelor of Arts Degree in Fine Arts and Web Development.

Diploma in Software Engineering, 2002

London Tec International, Sri Lanka.

Diploma in Hardware Engineering and Networking, 2003-2004

Turnkey Computer System, Sri Lanka.

CERTIFICATIONS:

Amazon Web Services (AWS), 2022

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner, In Progress.

Diablo Valley College, Pleasant Hill, CA, 2015 to 2018

Certificate of Achievement in Web Technology & Web Graphics.

Certified Internet Web Professional, 2012

Web Security Professional, Web Security Specialist, Web Security Associate, Security Essentials.

Microsoft Corporation, 2005 to 2008

 Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator on Windows Server, Technology Specialist, Desktop Support Technician, IT Professional, Enterprise Support Technician, Microsoft Certified Professional.

University of Colombo School of Computing, Advanced Digital Media Technology Centre, Sri Lanka, 2007 to 2008

• Certificate in Digital Video Production & 3D Animation.

Teleview Technology Academy, Sri Lanka, 2004 to 2005

• Certificate in 3D Graphics & Digital Animation.

Sri Lanka Institute of Printing, 2003 to 2004

Certificate in Typesetting, Graphic Design, and Web Design.

THILINA RANASINGHE Page 3

AWARDS AND HONORS

Top 10 Award Winner @ BestWeb.lk competition in 2010. Under Best Media, Sports & Entertainment Website category. Conducted by LK Domain Registry Sri Lanka.

VOLUNTEERISM

Preah Meada Kantey Cambodian Buddhist Association, Fresno, CA, Jan 2021 to Present

VOLUNTEER GRAPHICS WEB DESIGNER/SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER/IT SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR

- Pilot the development of the organization's website <u>www.PMKCBuddhistAssociation.org</u> including generating copy using SEO strategies, web hosting, and server management.
- Make event banners and flyers using Adobe Photoshop and Adobe Illustrator.

Hospital Services Support Foundation, San Ramon, CA, April 2019 to Present

VOLUNTEER GRAPHICS WEB DESIGNER/SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER/IT SUPPORT ADMINISTRATOR

- Establish and maintain the website <u>www.HospitalSSF.org</u> using WordPress and leveraging SEO techniques to drive traffic while managing the server.
- Create and manage official business pages on Facebook, YouTube, and Instagram as well as managing live events and designing event tickets, banners, brochures, and handouts.

Berkeley Buddhist Vihara, Richmond, CA, Sep 2018 to Present

VOLUNTEER AS TREASURER/GRAPHICS WEB DESIGNER/SOCIAL MEDIA MANAGER/IT SUPPORT

- Regulate bookkeeping using Wave Apps Online to collect donations and process transactions.
- Launch and manage the official website www.BerkeleyVihara.org apply SEO techniques, manage the server, and create official business pages on Facebook, YouTube, and Instagram.
- Coordinate live events on Facebook, YouTube, and Zoom, and design print and digital graphics.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Technical Proficiencies:

- Microsoft Windows, Apple iOS, Microsoft Office, Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, Dreamweaver, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Audition, Acrobat Pro, Sony Vegas Pro, 3D Studio Max, Garage Band, and Audacity.
- HTML / CSS / WordPress / WooCommerce / Shopify / Google Workspace (G Suite) / AWS / GoDaddy.
- Cloud Backup Storage (Google One, One Drive, Dropbox)